# **ALDO ISLAS**

#### • DETAILS •

Mexico City Mexico 52 55 42848859 aldo\_islasg@hotmail.com

# • SKILLS •

JavaScript

**Typescript** 

React js

Next js

Node.js

Python

Java

MongoDB

MySQL

SQL

PostgreSQL

HTML & CSS

Sass

**Taildwind** 

Sotorybook

AWS

Docker

## • LANGUAGES •

Spanish

English

#### HOBBIES

Exercise, read, technology

# PROFILE

Self-motivated hardworking Front end developer with 6+ years of experience. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting, eager to join to new projects to build innovative web applications.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Senior Front end software engineer at DigiSprint Solutions, Home office

November 2021 — Present

Client Liverpool.

Assigned to performance team focus on increase the performance of the actual e-commerce we increase from 14 % to 80 %. Refactor the full e commerce to implement good code practices, new technologies.

Refactor old react classes to functional components , hooks and last version improvements.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Typescript, react, next js, storybook, sass, HTML, CSS, tailwind, docker, Jest, React testing library.

## Senior Front end Developer at BlueDot, Home office

2019 - November 2021

Client Preparacion IPN

Development of the entire web platform for an educational business.

Admin dashboard with react, student platform with react and landing with next js.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Typescript, react, next js, storybook, sass, HTML, CSS, Jest, React testing library, AWS.

## Frontend developer at Plincos at Plincos, Mexico City

September 2017 — November 2018

Client Grupo Salinas.

Facebook Chatbot for Azteca bank to send money in Mexico from the chatbot.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Python

# Java developer at Omnitracs, Mexico City

August 2015 — October 2016

Development of modules, classes, interfaces for the current system, which is satellite and cellular tracking for trucks.

Technologies used: Java, PostgreSQL, Sprint

# Trainee Java developer at TATA, Mexico City

 ${\sf September\,2014-August\,2015}$ 

**Client Staples** 

Refactoring java class and interfaces and support for Staples e commerce system and database.

Technologies used: Java, Oracle DB

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Degree , Tecnológico de Estudios Superiores de Ecatepec

2010 - 2014